( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
( EERIE MUSIC CONTINUES )
( DOOR CREAKS )
MAN : Annie .
Daddy ?
- Dad ... - Go back to sleep .
- ( EERIE GROWL ) - ( ANNIE CRYING )
( SINISTER MUSIC PLAYING )
( DOOR CREAKS SOFTLY )
( LOW DEMONIC SNARLING )
( RUSTLING )
( DEMONIC GROWL )
MAN : Let me hold you .
( ANNIE CONTINUES CRYING )
( RUSTLING )
( SHUSHING ) It 's okay .
It 's just me .
( DISTORTED ) It 's your daddy .
- ( ANNIE SCREAMING ) - ( SINISTER MUSIC CONTINUES )
- It 's me ! - ( BLOOD SPLATS )
( MUSIC STOPS )
( DOOR CREAKS SOFTLY )
- ( DOOR SHUTS ) - ( EERIE MUSIC PLAYS )
( MUSIC FADES )
( DOOR CREAKS SOFTLY )
( WISTFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
( SNIFFING )
( WISTFUL MUSIC CONTINUES )
( ALARM BEEPING )
- ( LIGHT BALL THUDS ) - ( GASPING )
( ALARM STOPS )
( YAWNS )
( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
( GRUNTS )
WOMAN : I ...
might 've lost my cool a little .
Then I made an ultimatum .
Okay .
WOMAN : I 'm just scared that she 's stringing me along .
What are you scared of ?
WOMAN : That she doesn 't love me .
What are you really scared of ?
- Being alone . - Yeah .
I get it . It can be scary to be alone .
" Where there is fear ... "
" There is your task . "
( BOTH CHUCKLE )
Carl Jung had it figured out .
- ( FOOTSTEPS ) - ( FLOOR CREAKS )
Uh , that 's a good place to end for today .
I gotta get my kids to school . ( INHALES )
It 's been a month .
It 's their first day back . They 're a little anxious .
Not that they should be standing
right outside the door .
WOMAN : I feel like such a jerk .
None of my shit compares to what you 're dealing with .
Well , we 're not here to talk about me .
After you .
- You got your pencils ? - SAWYER : Yes .
Okay . What about your math book ?
SAWYER : Yes .
Uh , wait a minute . Did you brush your teeth ?
- Yes . Yes . - You did ?
Do you wanna use the bathroom , or no ?
SAWYER : No .
WILL : Sadie , come on ! We 're gonna be late !
Sadie ...
SADIE : What ?
Nothing .
( SENTIMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING )
Looks nice on you .
Just , uh , put on a jacket ' cause we 're gonna ...
It 's cold out there .
SAWYER : What if I accidentally swallow it ?
SADIE : Then it 'll come out in your shit .
WILL : It 's not gonna come out in your shit .
- Sadie . - SADIE : Back . Forward .
I don 't think you should keep pulling it .
- Pull it out . - No , don 't give her
- that advice . - SADIE : What ? Yes .
Don 't give her that ... Don 't listen to ...
- No , no , no . Don 't ... - Should I go soft or hard ?
- No , no , no , don 't listen ... - SADIE : Hard .
Put on your seat belt , please .
- Okay , jeez . - Mom would know what to do .
( MUSIC PLAYING SOFTLY ON SPEAKERS )
Well , I could pull it out myself .
- How would you like that ? - SAWYER : What ?
- Let me pull it out . - SAWYER : What ? ( LAUGHS )
WILL : I 'll pull it out right now . I 'm gonna pull it out .
( SAWYER AND SADIE LAUGH )
( SCHOOL BELL RINGS )
( MUFFLED CHATTER )
- You okay ? - SADIE : I 'm fine .
Have a great day .
( STUDENTS CHATTERING )
( MELLOW INDIE ROCK SONG PLAYING )
( MUFFLED ) Hey . Hey , Sadie .
I 'm ... I 'm sorry about your mom .
BOY 1 : Uh , sorry about your mom .
BOY 2 : Sorry , Sadie .
BOY 3 : You 're back .
BOY 4 : Sorry , Sadie .
GIRL : Hey , Sadie . Sorry about your mom .
( MUSIC STOPS )
( STUDENTS CHATTERING )
GIRL : Hey .
Hey .
- What 's up ? - GIRL : I , uh ...
I still can 't believe it , you know ?
I know .
But , um , welcome back . ( CHUCKLES )
Oh , my God . That 's ... ( CHUCKLES )
That 's really stupid to say .
Thanks for , like , actually talking to me .
Everyone else is staring at me
like I have some kind of disease .
You 're sick ?
- That 's so shitty . - SADIE : No , I ...
( CHUCKLES ) Just forget it .
You know , I like your dress .
I 'd wear it if I could pull it off .
It 's like a ... It 's like a statement .
- ANNE : Yeah , it 's cute . - Thanks .
- CASSIDY : Yeah . - I mean , it was my mom 's .
Are you sure that 's a good idea ?
Why am I sure what 's a good idea ?
I ... I just ... Wearing her clothes ,
it seems like it might make it harder to move on ,
or whatever .
I don 't wanna " move on . "
Okay . Maybe you don 't want
- to creep people out either . - Nat , come on .
NATALIE : What ? I 'm just ... BETHANY : Let 's not ...
I 'm just trying to help .
( SOFTLY ) No , you 're being a bitch .
CASSIDY : Wait , hold on .
- I 'm sorry . What did you say ? - Nat . Nat ...
- No , what did you say ? - I said you 're being a bitch .
CASSIDY : No , no , no , Natalie ! Let 's not ...
BETHANY : ( GASPS ) Oh , my God .
CASSIDY : Natalie , what did you do ?
- ( CHUCKLES ) - No , stop .
( SOMBER MUSIC PLAYS )
Do you need something
- to change into ? - Just leave me alone .
- Oh , my God . - You can 't laugh at that .
- Nat , what the hell ? - NATALIE : What ?
( CRYING QUIETLY )
WILL : That 's okay . You 're gonna get there .
- Just be patient . - Okay .
Well , you 've been doing the same thing for 30 years ,
we 've been working together for what ? Two ?
Okay . Okay .
Thanks .
You got this .
I 'll see you next week .
( SIGHS )
( LOW EERIE MUSIC PLAYS )
( DOOR CREAKS )
Dr. Harper ?
Can I help you ?
I need to talk to you .
I 'm sorry , I don 't see anyone
without an initial phone consultation .
So , you 'll have to make an appointment .
Please .
If I don 't tell somebody ,
I don 't know what I 'm gonna do .
What 's your name ?
Lester .
Lester Billings .
Good to meet you , Lester .
Come in . I got a ...
I got a free hour .
- Thank you . - Please .
You wanna hang up your jacket ?
Might make you more comfortable .
Can you shut it ?
Excuse me ?
The door .
Sure .
I have a few forms I need you to fill out .
( RECORDER BEEPS )
I use this with all my new clients .
This is for record-keeping purposes only .
So anything you say in here
is strictly confidential .
Is that okay ?
Is this your first time seeing a therapist ?
LESTER : Mm-hmm .
Well , why don 't we start
with why you decided to see one now ?
I didn 't know where else to go , you know , I ...
I can 't go to a priest ' cause I 'm not Catholic .
I can 't go to a lawyer ' cause I didn 't commit a crime .
Even if everybody thinks I have .
Even if they all think I did it .
Did what , exactly ?
Killed my kids .
One at a time .
Killed them all .
I ... I came to you ' cause I thought
that you might understand .
I saw the story about your wife in the paper .
The car accident .
And ...
And I know that you know what it 's like
to lose someone that you love just like that .
What ... What were you saying about your children ?
What happened to your children ?
Well , the first one ,
our baby girl , she ...
she died from SIDS .
WILL : I 'm so sorry .
I can 't even imagine how difficult that must have been .
You have kids .
So , you can imagine .
( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
( LESTER SNIFFLES )
My next two kids died within a year of the first ,
one right after the other .
From natural causes too ?
Nothing natural about it .
Sucked the life right out of them .
Even if the first one was an accident ,
it still made us susceptible .
Susceptible ?
To what ?
( SOFTLY ) I don 't know exactly .
I only glimpsed it once .
Before my Annie 's neck broke .
( TENSE MUSIC PLAYING )
Before they died , my kids ...
I thought it was just their imaginations
getting the better of ' em .
And my oldest did try drawing it for me .
( RIPS PAPER )
( DISQUIETING MUSIC PLAYS )
What is this supposed to be ?
It 's the thing that comes for your kids
when you 're not paying attention .
( UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYS )
I 'm sorry . Um , do you mind if I step out ?
I just need to use the restroom .
You believe me , don 't you ?
Of course I do .
I 'll be right back .
Excuse me .
( OMINOUS MUSIC BUILDING UP )
Yes , this is Dr. William Harper .
I have a man in my office right now
who is not well .
I think he might be dangerous .
OPERATOR : Okay , do you want us to send a car out ?
You there ?
Sir , you still with me ?
Yes .
Can you please confirm your name ?
William Harper , yeah .
He came in right off the street . I ...
- You ever see him before ? - No .
Okay . You don 't know who he is ?
- No . - ( SOFT FOOTSTEPS )
( FLOOR CREAKS )
No , it 's just me . I 'm alone in the house .
- ( OPERATOR TALKS INDISTINCTLY ) - ( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS )
( MELLOW ROCK SONG PLAYING OVER EARBUDS )
( SNIFFING )
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS )
( SONG CONTINUES PLAYING OVER EARBUDS )
( MUFFLED OBJECTS DRAGGING )
( OBJECT CLATTERS )
Dad ?
( OBJECTS THUDDING )
( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
( MUFFLED THUMP )
( DISEMBODIED EERIE GROWL )
( SQUELCHING )
( GASPS )
- ( OBJECTS CLATTER ) - ( GASPING )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING )
( GRIM MUSIC PLAYING )
( CRYING )
( THUDDING )
( MUFFLED CHATTER )
( MUFFLED OBJECTS RATTLE )
( MUFFLED LAUGHTER )
( MUFFLED THWACK )
( MUFFLED CHATTER CONTINUES )
- ( MAN GROANING ) - ( LOUD CRASH )
( GASPS )
( WHISPERING ) Dad ?
( MUFFLED RATTLING )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( RATTLING STOPS )
( DOOR SLAMS OPEN )
( GASPING SHAKILY )
- WILL : You okay ? Are you okay ? - ( GASPING ) Yeah .
Okay . Okay , listen to me .
Listen , there 's a man in the house .
( SCREAMING )
( CHILDREN CHATTERING )
So gross .
I know , right ? I think it 's gonna come out today .
BOY 1 : Guys , guys , look !
( CLAMORING )
GIRL 1 : Is that Sawyer 's house ?
GIRL 2 : I see a dead body .
What 's under that white sheet ? There 's cops ...
GIRL 3 : Oh , shit !
Your dad 's not dead too , is he ?
WILL : ( MUFFLED ) I should 've called you guys right away ,
the minute he walked in my office .
No , he ...
He seemed sick .
He showed me this paper
and he had a drawing that his daughter did .
There was no blood on his hands
- or anything like that . - DET . GARLAND : Mm-hmm .
WILL : He kept talking about this ...
- shadow monster . - ( SIREN WAILING )
( POLICE RADIO CHATTER )
Shadow monster ?
He believed it killed all his kids .
I 've seen it before .
Sometimes it 's better to have
something to blame
than to admit these things happen for no reason .
SADIE : ( WHISPERS ) Hey .
It 's okay .
DET . GARLAND : Mm , I don 't buy that someone could lose
all three of their kids like that for no reason .
( WHISPERING ) What 's going on ?
Do you think he killed them ?
Guilt must have pushed him over the edge .
Or the fear of getting caught .
Are you sure it was a suicide ?
Sweetheart , let me handle ...
Sawyer .
Sadie , take Sawyer to her room .
- Please . - It 's okay . It 's all right .
It 's all right . Let her talk .
What do you mean , " are we sure ? "
Before I opened the closet ,
I heard these noises .
Like a fight or something .
DET . GARLAND : An adult man hanging himself
in a closet is bound to cause a racket .
That 's gotta be what you heard .
WILL : Don 't worry about that man , okay ?
If you get scared , you know where to find me .
- Are you tired ? - SAWYER : No .
WILL : Well , it 's late and we should go to sleep .
All right ?
There you go .
I don 't know how you sleep with all these lights .
Easy . Like this .
Fair enough .
All right , love .
You sleep well .
What 's goin ' on ?
Did you check under the bed ?
No , let me look . Let me see .
Uh ... All clear .
What about the closet ?
Mm , I don 't see anything .
Just can you please check ?
Definitely . Definitely .
And you know what ? I will bet you
that there 's nothing in there .
I 'll give you a dollar if there 's nothing in there .
Five dollars .
Okay . ( CHUCKLES )
You drive a hard bargain . Got a deal .
Put it there . ( GRUNTS PLAYFULLY )
No . Dad .
Okay . I 'm gonna go . Let 's see .
Well , congratulations . You 're five dollars richer .
- Are you sure ? - I 'm sure .
Okay , monster check complete .
Good night .
See you in the morning light .
( FOOTSTEPS DEPARTING )
( DOOR OPENS )
( DOOR CLOSES )
( FAINT EERIE MUSIC PLAYS )
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
WILL : Hey , Sadie . Just checking on you .
SADIE : Hmm .
Hey .
Hi .
You okay ?
( DOOR CLOSES )
I don 't know why this had to happen
on top of everything else .
Does it remind you of when Mom died ?
Did you have to talk to a bunch of police and stuff ?
No .
You never talk about it .
I wasn 't at the accident .
So there 's no one I had to talk to .
I just ...
It doesn 't feel real .
I keep thinking she 's gonna come through that door
with a cardamom tea that smells like shit .
You know , I never even
got to say goodbye .
Since she died , I feel like ...
like this weight .
This extra gravity .
It 's just ...
You have Dr. Weller tomorrow , right ?
Yeah .
You should talk to her about this .
I was trying to talk to you .
Yeah . Yeah .
Well , it 's been a long day .
We should probably hit the hay .
I 'll see you in the morning .
Sleep happy .
( GLOOMY MUSIC PLAYING )
( WASHING MACHINE CHIMES )
( RUSTLING )
( RUSTLING CONTINUES )
( DOOR SLAMS OPEN )
( GASPS )
- ( BREATHING SHAKILY ) - ( DOOR CREAKING )
( CREAKING )
( SAWYER GASPS )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( LIGHT BALL THUDS )
( GASPS )
- ( RUSTLING ) - ( GASPS )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
- ( ROARS ) - ( SAWYER SCREAMS )
( SCREAMS , GRUNTS )
... a particular loved one .
But just focus on that flame
and you can say it out loud yourself .
" Spirit , if you are here today ,
" please bend the flame to the left . "
Now , just think about the loved one
that you would like to communicate with .
Just imagine them , picture them in your mind .
Think of ...
About how you feel about them .
About , um , how they look .
Any ... Any strong memories
that you have , you have of them .
Picture their face .
How you feel when you 're with them .
Our loved ones are with us always .
If you 're there , bend the flame
- to the left . - SAWYER : Sadie ?
Hey .
You having trouble sleeping ?
Sawyer ?
SAWYER : There 's something in my room .
( SIGHS ) Sawyer , you were just having a nightmare .
Oh , man .
- And you 're bleeding . - I fell out of bed .
- Say " ah . " - Ah .
SADIE : Yeah , I found the culprit .
Might be time for that little guy to come out .
This is what Mom did whenever I had a tooth
that wouldn 't come out on its own .
She said that deep roots run in our family .
Don 't like letting go of things .
So , I 'm gonna count to three ,
and I 'm gonna slam the door .
( MOUTH FULL ) On three ? Or after three ?
( CHUCKLES ) On three , okay ?
Okay .
- One , two ... - Wait !
We don 't have to do this ...
( CRYING )
I 'm so sorry !
- You said on three ! - I don 't know what happened .
Hey , hey , hey .
( SADIE HUMMING )
( SINGING ) Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Loo-Ra
Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Li
Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Loo-Ra
Hush now , don 't you cry
CROAKY MALE VOICE : ( SINGING ) Too-Ra-Loo-Ra
( SOFT GROWL )
Too-Ra
Loo-Ra-Ra
Too-Ra-Loo-Ra
Hush now , don 't you cry
Loo-Ra-Loo-Ra-Loo-Ra
( DISTORTED GROWLING )
( IN SADIE 'S VOICE ) Hush now , don 't you cry
What do you think happens to people after they die ?
Now , what do you mean , Sadie ?
Do you mean do they go to Heaven ?
No , that 's not what I mean .
Are you wondering if maybe your mother is still here ?
This may seem a little out there , but ...
when my father passed away ,
I felt like I could sense him
watching over me sometimes .
If you pay close enough attention ,
maybe you 'll start sensing your mom , too .
What about other things ?
What other things ?
I don 't know .
It 's hard to see . It 's like ...
a dark thing .
I see .
Well , when did you start seeing this dark thing ?
Right after that man died .
That makes perfect sense .
Okay .
So , what is it ?
DR. WELLER : Well , when there are scary things
we don 't understand ,
our minds try to fill in the blanks .
But it 's just like all those spooky monsters
you think are hiding under your bed .
DR. WELLER : But we 're going to work on that together .
Okay ?
So , it 's not so scary .
( WHIRRING )
Now , we talked about this last time .
When we have a phobia
or fear something ,
sometimes the best thing to do
is to face it .
And that 's what we 're gonna do today .
So , this light is gonna be completely solid
like it is right now .
Then gradually it 's gonna start flashing ,
slowly bringing the room down till it 's totally dark .
So you can see that there 's nothing to be afraid of .
Okay ?
I 'm ready . ( SHUDDERS )
Okay , good girl . Let 's start .
( LIGHT CLICKS )
That 's not so scary , is it ?
See ? Same old boring office as before .
( SNIFFLING SOFTLY )
Just you , your sister
and me .
You doin ' okay ?
No .
( SAWYER BREATHING HEAVILY )
( LIGHT RATTLES )
Hey , hey , hey .
It 's all right . It 's all right .
- You 're so close . - I don 't want to .
SADIE : No . Sawyer , you got this .
- It 's not real . It 's not real . - ( SAWYER WHIMPERING )
Hey , you 're doing so good .
It 's not real .
DR. WELLER : Good job .
SADIE : It 's not real . It 's all in your head .
DR. WELLER : Remember , nothing to be scared of .
( SADIE SHUSHING )
( SAWYER BREATHING SHAKILY )
SADIE : It 's all in your head .
( ECHOING ) It 's not real . You got this .
It 's almost over .
It 's not real .
( SADIE SHUSHING )
( SNARLING )
( SNARLS )
- ( HOWLS ) - ( SCREAMS )
DR. WELLER : ( MUFFLED ) Hey !
It was only your imagination .
SADIE : You did it .
- DR . WELLER : Oh . Oh ... - Sawyer , it 's okay .
- It 's fine . - DR . WELLER : No need to worry .
- It 's okay . - DR . WELLER : Yeah .
Now you don 't have to do that again .
DR. WELLER : It 's not just a fear of the dark .
She 's claiming to see monsters now .
WILL : Yep . Yeah , I heard about the monster .
We talked about the monster .
DR. WELLER : They want to speak with you now .
I think next ... next session would be the proper time .
WILL : Yeah , I know .
It doesn 't seem like the right time for me ,
but eventually I 'll come in .
DR. WELLER : We have to talk about your wife .
You believe me ,
don 't you ?
Yeah .
WILL : I got this under control .
- Thank you very much . - DR . WELLER : Will ,
you can 't avoid talking about her forever .
WILL : Guys ready ? Let 's go .
( SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING )
I 'm really sorry .
I should have never let that man in our house .
( KEYBOARD CLACKING )
( SIGHS )
( DOOR OPENS )
( DOOR CREAKING )
( FOOTSTEPS )
( BED CREAKS )
SADIE : You doin ' okay ?
SAWYER : Not really .
SADIE : Try to go to sleep .
Just trying not to die , thanks .
SADIE : It 's all just in your head .
It 's not real .
Sadie ?
( DOOR CREAKS SOFTLY )
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
WILL : ( ON RECORDING ) I do this with all my new clients ,
but it 's for record-keeping purposes only .
- SAWYER : Sadie ? - ( LIGHT CLICKS )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
Sadie ?
- MALE VOICE : It 's not real . - ( GASPS )
( FOOTSTEPS SCATTER )
LESTER : My next two kids died within a year of the first ,
one right after the other .
Even if the first one was an accident ,
it still made us susceptible .
WILL : Susceptible ?
To what ?
LESTER : I only glimpsed it once .
Before my Annie 's neck broke .
Before they died , my kids ,
I thought it was just their imaginations
getting the better of ' em and ...
So , my oldest , she tried drawing it for me .
( PAPER RUSTLING ON RECORDING )
SADIE : ( SINGING ) Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Loo-Ra
Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Li
- Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Loo - ( SOFT RUSTLING )
( VOICE DISTORTING ) Hush now , don 't you cry
I know that 's you , Sadie .
- DISTORTED VOICE : Sawyer . - ( GASPING )
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
WILL : What is this supposed to be ?
LESTER : It 's the thing that comes for your kids
when you 're not paying attention .
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( LIGHT BALL THUDS )
- ( LIGHT BALL THUDS ) - ( GASPS SOFTLY )
( GASPS )
LESTER : You believe me , don 't you ?
WILL : Of course I do .
LESTER : ( TEARILY ) No !
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
No , no .
( SOBBING ) No . No !
I 'm sorry , Annie .
I 'm sorry , Scott . I never believed you .
I never believed you .
I 'm so sorry , Sophie .
I 'm so sorry .
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
( GASPS )
Get away from me . You get away ...
- ( SCREAMS ) Get away from me ! - ( GASPS )
Shit !
( SIGHING )
( SIGHS IN RELIEF )
( LIGHT CRACKLES )
( WATER PATTERING SOFTLY )
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
- ( GRUNTS ) - Hey ! What was that for ?
That was a mean prank !
How are you doing that with your voice ?
What are you talking about ?
- ( GRUNTS ) - Ow !
- Sawyer , it wasn 't me ! - Liar !
- Ow , Sawyer ! - Liar !
( DISQUIETING MUSIC PLAYING )
Is this the dark thing that you 've been seeing ?
Yeah .
Is it real ?
I don 't know .
But I 'm gonna find out .
- ( SCHOOL BELL RINGING ) - ANNE : It was just ...
Yeah , it wasn 't really a big deal ,
I don 't think , but it was fine .
CASSIDY : I have nothin ' to wear .
ANNE : But it 's , you know , at the same time I think
- about it , it 's like ... - Uh-oh , drama alert .
( CHUCKLES )
Guys , be nice . She just lost her mom .
I haven 't seen my dad in , like , a year ,
and I seriously don 't give a ...
Can I talk to you ?
Um , yeah . Of course .
Alone .
( CHUCKLES ) Okay .
What is her deal ?
Have fun .
CASSIDY : Which class y 'all got next ?
I 'm sorry about the other day . It was ...
Do you wanna make it up to me ?
BETHANY : Of course . Yeah , anything .
SADIE : Can you give me a ride ?
( GRIM MUSIC PLAYS )
You sure this is the right place ?
Just wait here .
You 're not seriously going in ?
Sadie ?
Sadie !
- ( CAR DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES ) - ( SWING CREAKING )
- ( KNOCKING ON DOOR ) - SADIE : Hello ?
( GRIM MUSIC CONTINUES )
( GLASS CRUNCHING UNDERFOOT )
Hello ?
Is anybody home ?
( CELL PHONE VIBRATING )
What ?
BETHANY : Are you , like , buying drugs or something ?
No . What ... I 'm not buying drugs .
I know things have been hard for you lately , but I ...
Just wanna see if anyone still lived here .
Oh , I really hope not . That 'd be , like ,
- the saddest thing ever . - ( FLIES BUZZING )
What is this place ?
- ( GASPS ) - Sadie , what was that ?
Wait a second .
Coming back now .
( LIGHT CRACKLES )
Sadie , what 's going on ?
Is there someone there ?
( UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING )
Hello ?
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( LIGHT CRACKLES )
( DROPS WHIP )
( SIGHS IN RELIEF )
- ( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING ) - ( RUSTLING )
( GASPS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( EERIE MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING )
Hello ?
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
Is anybody here ?
( EERIE MUSIC CONTINUES )
( SOFT CLICKING )
( CAMERA CLICKS , WHIRS )
( GASPS )
( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS )
WOMAN : This some kind of a dare ?
You think it 'd be fun to get off on our misery ?
Maybe get a souvenir .
No . N ...
I 'm Sadie .
Sadie Harper .
Your husband , Lester , came to see my dad .
( COCKS GUN )
I just ...
I wanted to ask about ...
- What ? - This right here .
WOMAN : Where 'd you get this ?
I just wanna know what it is .
You should pray to God you never find out .
Get outta here before you get yourself hurt .
My ... My sister saw it .
Oh , Les , what have you done ?
Must 've latched on to you now .
Goes after the hurt and the vulnerable .
Follows you wherever you go .
Until you 're all gone .
That 's what happened to your kids ?
They called it ...
" The Boogeyman . "
Yeah , that 's the way I used to look at them .
Like they were crazy .
I found out the hard way I was wrong .
It likes to play with its food .
Scare ' em to death .
Shit , it can even talk like them .
Like a goddamn echo .
And it needs the dark to stay hidden .
Fire was the first thing man used to see at night .
It 's really been around that long ?
I think it 's been around forever .
( DISQUIETING MUSIC PLAYS )
( MUSIC STOPS )
( SOFTLY ) Don 't move .
It 's right behind you .
Don 't turn around .
Stay in the light .
And stay completely ...
still .
- ( GUN FIRING ) - ( SADIE SCREAMS )
WOMAN : I see you , you son of a bitch !
Sadie ! Hey , was that a gunshot ?
- Sadie ! Sadie ! Are you okay ? - I 'm fine .
It 's just some crazy bitch .
BETHANY : Sadie ...
SADIE : Let 's get outta here .
( SIGHS )
SAWYER : Sadie ?
What happened to you ?
( SIGHS ) Sawyer , I can 't right now .
Sadie ? Wait , what happened ?
SADIE : Leave me alone , Sawyer .
SAWYER : Sadie , did you see it ?
There 's no such thing as monsters .
You need to grow up !
- Sadie ! - ( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
I 'm serious , Sawyer .
I need to be alone right ...
- ( SADIE SCREAMS ) - ( BOOGEYMAN ROARS )
( GASPING )
( COUGHING )
( PANTING )
( MUFFLED BANGING )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( MUFFLED OBJECTS KNOCKING AND RATTLING )
( MUFFLED OBJECT SCRAPING )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
I told you it was real .
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( MUFFLED BANGING )
( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
- ( DOOR BANGS ) - ( FOOTSTEPS )
( DOOR OPENS )
What are you doing ?
Where is everything ?
It 's not a good idea for us
to keep her stuff lying around .
No wonder Sawyer 's seeing ghosts .
How could you do this without even asking ?
You 're just gonna get rid of all her stuff ?
Sometimes I have to make decisions
that you might not understand .
- How I feel doesn 't count ? - That 's not what I said .
- Don 't put words in my mouth . - That 's how you act !
You barely pay attention to anything I say !
It 's like you don 't even give a shit
- about Mom anymore . - You don 't know how I feel !
So tell me !
You 're right . I 'm sorry .
I shouldn 't have done that without asking you .
Keep what you want .
What if I wanna keep all of it ?
Then we 'll keep all of it .
Just take it down to the basement for me .
( SOLEMN MUSIC PLAYING )
( SENTIMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING )
( BEEPS )
CARA : ( SINGING ) Ral-Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Li
Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Loo-Ral
Hush now , don 't you cry
Just a simple little ditty
In her good old Irish way
And I 'd give the world if I could hear
That song of hers today
WILL : That 's beautiful . Keep going .
CARA : ( SCOFFS ) Liar .
WILL : She loves it .
CARA : You 're such a liar .
I have a terrible voice .
( BEEPS )
( INHALES DEEPLY )
Mom ...
if you 're here ,
bend the flame to the left .
Please .
I could really use your help right now .
BOOGEYMAN : ( IN CARA 'S VOICE ) I have a terrible voice .
( CLATTERING AND CREAKING )
( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( MUSIC BUILDING UP )
( SHUDDERING )
CARA AND WILL : ( SINGING ) Ra-Loo-Ra-Loo-Ral
Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Li
Too-Ra-Loo-Ra-Loo-Ral
WILL : Sadie .
- ( BABY SADIE COOS ) - Who is that ?
WILL : Hi .
CARA : Is that Daddy ?
CARA : Boop . ( LAUGHS )
- Boop . - ( KNOCKING ON STALL DOOR )
Wait . Do you mind ?
Well , it 's not like you 're peeing .
Not that I haven 't seen you pee a thousand times before .
What 's going on with you ?
- Nothing . - BETHANY : Come on , it 's not nothing .
The house I took you to , the gunshot .
( SIGHS ) It 's too hard to explain .
I 'm probably just losing my mind .
What are you doing ?
I 'm not leaving until you tell me
what 's going on .
Come on , I 'm your best friend .
You were my best friend .
Now you have all these new friends
who are so much cooler .
That is not true .
They 're your friends , too .
When was the last time that we hung out ?
Your mom 's funeral .
That doesn 't count .
Well , let 's hang out .
This weekend even , we can all come over .
( CHUCKLES DRYLY )
I ... I ... I don 't need a pity party .
It 's not a pity party .
- That 's not what this is . - ( DOOR OPENS )
( GIRLS LAUGHING )
- It won 't be . - ( DOOR CLOSES )
Look , I have no idea what you 're dealing with ,
but you shouldn 't be dealing with this alone , all right ?
Come on .
( FOLK ROCK SONG PLAYING )
( CHUCKLES )
Yes !
( SADIE LAUGHS )
( SONG CONTINUES OVER SPEAKERS )
WILL : So , this is a big night for your sister , okay ?
So , you see any monsters , you come get me first .
Let 's give her the night off .
That sound okay ?
And you 'll let me sleep in your bed ?
Yeah , I 'll let you sleep in my bed
if you stop eating the cheese
' cause you 're gonna be farting all night .
Let 's make a deal . Okay ?
I will let you play PlayStation
for as long as you want .
Screen time is officially suspended .
Just let her have a nice night .
- Deal ? - Deal .
- Deal . Give me the cheese . - WILL : Wait , wait .
- What are you guys betting on ? - We 're not betting .
We 're agreeing to stay out
- of the way tonight . Right ? - ( DOORBELL RINGS )
Oh , shit . That 's them . ( SIGHS )
I look okay ?
You look ...
beautiful .
You look like you 're about to forget
all your worries and your strife .
Jungle Book .
Remember ? You used to love that . We used to dance .
( SINGING ) Bare necessities
Just don 't say anything , okay ?
- ( SAWYER GRUNTS ) - ( SADIE BREATHING HEAVILY )
( INDIE ROCK SONG PLAYING )
- Hey ! Hi ! - ( ALL EXCLAIM AND LAUGH )
( MUSIC STOPS )
( MUFFLED DOWNTEMPO SONG PLAYING ON SPEAKERS )
Do you have anything else to drink ?
Like other kinds of soda ?
No , like alcohol .
Sorry , my dad 's not much of a drinker , so ...
That you know of .
Nat .
Well , I ... I do have something else , though .
Oh ?
Like , actual drugs . ( CHUCKLES )
Wait , what ? ( CHUCKLES )
Okay .
( CHUCKLES )
SADIE : Cool .
Actual drugs .
( GIGGLES )
Since when do you smoke ?
It was my mom 's .
( WHISPERING ) Oh , shit .
But it 's ... it 's cool .
I mean , it 's not like she 's coming back to get it .
You sure ?
Yeah .
All right , this is probably out of lighter fluid .
Okay , let me just ...
Amateurs .
There .
( ALL LAUGH )
Now you .
In honor of your mom .
Thanks .
( COUGHING )
Definitely popping your cherry right now , huh ?
( ALL LAUGHING )
This is so sweet .
- BETHANY : You all right ? - ( COUGHING )
You need water or something ?
SADIE : ( COUGHING ) It 's all right .
- You okay ? - SADIE : Oh , my God . Yeah .
ANNE : I think you need to go to ...
( CONTINUES COUGHING )
Are you sure you 're good ?
BETHANY : Do you need some water ?
CASSIDY : Take a deep breath .
( CONTINUES COUGHING )
( GAGGING )
( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
( RETCHES )
( GASPS )
- ( KNOCK ON DOOR ) - Oh , God . It made you sick ?
- You feel all right ? - I 'm fine .
- Are you sure ? - I 'm fine .
So cute . Oh , my God , guys !
( CHUCKLES ) Say cheese !
BETHANY : Guys , come on . Don 't .
SADIE : What are you doing ?
I ... I wasn 't even recording .
Are you sure you 're okay ?
I 'm fine .
ANNE : I should make myself throw up . I ate so much pizza .
BETHANY : No , it was the weed . It made her sick .
Hey , isn 't this the closet
where that crazy guy hung himself ?
No , that was the closet in my mom 's studio .
Could you show it to us ?
ANNE : Shit , that 'd be sick . NATALIE : ( CHUCKLES ) Right ?
( DOOR CREAKS )
Where was he hanging from ?
He was right around the back of ...
( SOFT RUSTLING )
SADIE : What are you doing ? BETHANY : Nat , come on .
- Oh , my God . - SADIE : What are you ...
NATALIE : It 's called exposure therapy .
- BETHANY : Don 't ! - SADIE : Guys !
- Come on ! - WOMAN : Oh , God .
This isn 't funny !
NATALIE : It 's not a big deal . Just chill .
- ( NATALIE LAUGHING ) - ( SOFT GROWL )
- ( BOOGEYMAN ROARS ) - ( SADIE SCREAMS )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
BOOGEYMAN : ( IN CARA 'S VOICE ) I have a terrible voice .
( ROARING )
SADIE : Please !
- Please ! - ( BANGING ON DOOR )
- ( BOOGEYMAN ROARS ) - ( SADIE SCREAMS )
BETHANY : Oh , my God . Are you okay ?
( CLAMORING )
- ( SADIE GRUNTS ) - Hey , hey , hey , Sadie .
ANNE AND CASSIDY : What happened ?
Are you okay ? Was there something in there ?
Was there something in there ?
No , she 's just being dramatic .
- ( YELPS ) - ( GIRLS EXCLAIM )
- What is wrong with you ? - Oh , my God ! God , Sadie ,
- the door would not open ! - NATALIE : You psycho bitch !
I swear , we were all trying .
You are such a liar !
ANNE : Keep your hands to your ...
And you 're a freak !
Bethany is literally the only person in here
who actually likes you .
- Literally schizophrenic ! - ANNE : Oh , my God .
- She 's crazy ! - Are you okay ?
NATALIE : No ! WILL : What 's going on , guys ?
ANNE : Your daughter is psychotic .
( VIDEO GAME SOUNDS PLAYING )
NATALIE : I 'm so done with her .
You are never gonna hang out with her again .
BETHANY : She 's literally never done anything like ...
NATALIE : I can 't believe she slapped me !
ANNE : Dude , are you okay ?
BETHANY : I mean , she 's never done anything ...
( DOOR CLOSES )
( FLOOR CREAKING )
- ( VIDEO GAME CHIMES ) - ( GASPS )
( VIDEO GAME SOUNDS PLAYING )
- ( BOOGEYMAN GRUNTS ) - ( GASPS )
( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
( BOOGEYMAN SNARLING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
- ( FOOTSTEPS THUDDING ) - ( BOOGEYMAN GROWLING )
SADIE 'S VOICE : Sawyer .
( SOFT WHEEZE )
( RASPILY ) Sawyer .
( GASPS )
- ( WHEEZING ) - ( FOOTSTEPS THUDDING )
( DISTORTED ) Sawyer .
( FOOTSTEPS FADE )
( UNNERVING MUSIC BUILDING UP )
- ( MUSIC FADES ) - ( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( SCREAMS )
( GASPS )
- ( SCREAMING ) - ( BOOGEYMAN ROARING )
- ( ROARING STOPS ) - ( YELPS )
( SOLEMN MUSIC PLAYING )
( MUFFLED ) Sawyer . Hey , hey !
Sawyer ! Sawyer !
Come on , come on ! Sawyer !
Go !
Hey , hey .
MAN : Get 911 !
- WILL : Sawyer ! - ( GASPING )
- It 's okay . It 's okay . - It tried to kill me .
- I know . I saw it too . - I had to get away .
( CONTINUES GASPING )
I believe you .
What ?
I 'm sorry I didn 't before .
Where 's Dad ?
He went to go talk to a doctor ,
but I 'm gonna find him . We 're gonna go home .
No , no , no . Don 't go .
- No . - Please , don 't go .
I 'm gonna be right back , okay ?
( WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON PA )
( CELL PHONE VIBRATING )
Hello ?
Hey , it 's Rita Billings .
Lester 's wife .
What do you want ?
I found a way to get rid of it .
How ?
I need your help . Get over here .
We can end this tonight .
Sadie ?
Sadie ...
Dad ?
( EXHALES ) Hey .
What are you doing ?
Nothing . Uh ...
Go ... Go back to your sister . I 'll be ...
I 'll be right there .
Well , I can tell it 's not nothing .
They brought Mom here after the car accident .
And now Sawyer .
This is all my fault .
I didn 't do enough to help her process it ,
so now she 's having these ... these manifestations .
Oh , Dad , stop . They 're not manifestations .
Then what is it ?
What is it ?
It 's real .
I saw something tonight .
In the closet .
What does it look like ?
- I mean , was it ... - SADIE : It was really dark in there .
Couldn 't tell .
I 'm gonna ask you a question , okay ?
I don 't want you to get mad .
What ?
Were you high ?
I could smell weed on you .
A monster in a closet ?
Know what ? Never mind .
- You never listen to me . - Wait .
Sadie , where you going ?
To deal with the problem . Somebody has to .
( BROODING MUSIC PLAYING )
( CELL PHONE VIBRATING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( TENSE MUSIC PLAYING )
RITA : I wasn 't sure you 'd come .
SADIE : I had to .
That thing tried to kill my little sister tonight .
It must be getting hungry .
You 're almost out of time .
If it 's weakness it 's drawn to ,
then we 've gotta show it strength .
Whoa , whoa , whoa .
Watch your step .
Spring-loaded firing pins .
Wouldn 't wanna see your head get taken off .
Normally , they 're used
to scare off bears when you 're camping ,
but they 're not normally loaded with live rounds .
( TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES )
You think you can kill it ?
Only one way to find out .
- ( SADIE YELPS ) - ( GRUNTING )
No ! ( WHIMPERING )
I 'm sorry !
I needed something to draw it out !
No !
I won 't let anything happen to you .
SADIE : No ! RITA : You just gotta trust me .
( SADIE CRYING )
( BOOGEYMAN GROWLING )
BOOGEYMAN : Sadie .
( LOW GROANING )
( WHOOSHING )
( WHIMPERING )
( BOOGEYMAN GROWLING )
( GROWLING STOPS )
( LOW GROWL )
( BREATHING SHARPLY )
- ( ROARS ) - ( TRAP PINGS )
( BOOGEYMAN ROARING )
( GASPING )
( DISQUIETING MUSIC PLAYING )
( SADIE SCREAMING )
( SPITS )
Told you it could be killed .
- ( BOOGEYMAN ROARING ) - ( RITA SCREAMING )
( BOOGEYMAN ROARING )
Sadie !
Sadie , help !
Sadie , help me !
- Sadie ... - ( BOOGEYMAN ROARS )
- ( SADIE GASPING ) - ( BOOGEYMAN ROARING )
( CONTINUES ROARING )
( GRUNTING )
( BOOGEYMAN SHRIEKING )
( GASPING )
( DOOR OPENS )
( DOG BARKS IN DISTANCE )
( CELL PHONE VIBRATING )
( SOBS ) Dad ?
Where have you been ?
We 've been driving around looking for you .
You guys are home ?
WILL : Yeah , we just got back . Why ?
Listen to me , just go back to the car .
Go somewhere bright with lots of people .
You need to get outta there
- before it comes back . - Wait . Slow down .
Dad , you have to listen to me .
Okay . I 'm listening .
SADIE : ( MUFFLED ) Go somewhere with lots of light
and lots of people , okay ?
Dad . Dad ?
( BOTH SCREAM )
( GASPING )
( TENSE MUSIC PLAYING )
( PANTING )
( SWITCH CLICKING )
( SINISTER MUSIC PLAYING )
( WATER PATTERING )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( GASPS )
( SINISTER MUSIC CONTINUES )
- ( SAWYER SCREAMS ) - SADIE : God !
Sawyer , it 's me !
SADIE : How do I know it 's really you ?
( PANTING )
You had your sixth birthday party
at Chuck E. Cheese . ( SNIFFLES )
You ate too much pizza
and then you threw up in the ball pit .
Oh , my God .
Sawyer ! Are you okay ? What happened ?
- What happened ? - It doesn 't like the light .
( SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS )
Where 's Dad ?
SAWYER : It took him down there .
We are not going to lose him , too .
Sadie ,
what are you doing ? Where are you going ?
Sadie , don 't leave me here .
You 'll be safe .
I saw it bleed . It can be hurt .
Maybe we can stop it .
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( TENSE MUSIC PLAYING )
( GASPING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GRUNTS )
( OBJECTS CLATTER LOUDLY )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( BOOGEYMAN GROWLING )
( GASPING )
( BOOGEYMAN ROARING )
( SAWYER SCREAMS )
SADIE : Sawyer !
( BOOGEYMAN GROWLS , ROARS )
( PANTING )
( BOOGEYMAN ROARS )
Sawyer , get up !
Please . Sawyer !
( BOOGEYMAN ROARING )
( WHIMPERING )
( GRUNTING AND WHIMPERING )
( CONTINUES WHIMPERING )
( BOOGEYMAN GROWLING )
( GASPING )
( CHOKING )
- ( LOW GROWL ) - ( GROANING SOFTLY )
BOOGEYMAN : ( IN CARA 'S VOICE ) Hush now .
- ( BOOGEYMAN GROWLING ) - ( SADIE CHOKING )
- ( WILL SHOUTS ) - ( BOOGEYMAN ROARS )
( GASPS )
( GRUNTING )
- SAWYER : No ! - Dad !
Dad !
Sawyer !
( SAWYER GRUNTS )
- ( BOOGEYMAN GROANING SOFTLY ) - ( SADIE GRUNTS )
Sawyer ?
( SAWYER WHIMPERS SOFTLY )
Sawyer ? Sawyer , it 's me , Sadie .
Look at me , please . Come on .
Hey . We 're gonna get outta here .
( LIGHTER CLICKS )
( BOOGEYMAN GROWLING )
- Dad . - SAWYER : Give me that .
Grab his arm . Grab his arm . Come on . Get him up .
SADIE : We 've gotta get him outta here .
- WILL : I can 't . - Come on . Yes , you can .
Come on .
( GROANING IN PAIN )
Get him up . Get him .
I 'm sorry .
( SADIE SNIFFLES )
( TENSE MUSIC PLAYING )
( SAWYER CRYING )
( MUSIC BUILDING UP )
( MUSIC HALTS )
( BOOGEYMAN GROWLS )
- SAWYER : Sadie ? - ( LIGHTER CLICKING )
( LOW GROWLING )
( SADIE BREATHING SHAKILY )
( BOOGEYMAN ROARS , GROWLS )
( BREATH SHUDDERS )
( BOOGEYMAN GROANS , GROWLS )
( PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING )
( SOFTLY ) Mom .
Sadie ?
- ( BOOGEYMAN ROARING ) - ( ALL SCREAMING )
Sawyer !
- ( GROWLS ) - ( WILL GRUNTS )
( BOOGEYMAN ROARING )
( BOOGEYMAN SHRIEKING )
( GRUNTS )
- ( BREATH SHUDDERING ) - ( AIR HISSING )
( BOOGEYMAN GROWLS )
- ( GRUNTS ) - ( GROWLING )
Fuck you .
( ROARING )
( INDISTINCT VOICES SHOUTING AND SCREAMING )
( SOLEMN MUSIC PLAYING )
( VOICES CONTINUE SHOUTING AND SCREAMING )
( ROARS LOUDLY )
( VOICES SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
( VOICES FADE )
( SORROWFUL MUSIC PLAYING )
( WILL GRUNTING )
Goodbye .
( FIRE ROARING )
( WILL COUGHING )
( ALL GRUNTING )
( WILL GROANS )
( SAWYER AND WILL COUGHING )
SADIE : We 're almost there .
SAWYER : Come on .
( WILL GRUNTING )
( WILL COUGHING )
( MUSIC FADING )
( ALL BREATHING HEAVILY )
I was terrified .
To be honest with you ...
I was scared to be a dad .
I was scared .
I didn 't ... I didn 't know if I could handle it .
Or if I was ready .
Mom made it all look easy .
Nothing fazed her , you know ?
And I ...
I figured ...
when I screwed up , that she 'd always be there .
And then ...
Then all of a sudden she wasn 't .
I see so much of her in you girls .
So much .
I never planned on doing any of this without Mom .
( SOFTLY ) No .
But I know we can handle it .
Yeah .
- Right ? - Mm-hmm .
( GENTLE MUSIC PLAYING )
( WILL SIGHS )
That sucked .
( ALL LAUGH )
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
SAWYER : Yeah , because it 's bread ,
and bagels are bread .
DR. WELLER : Sadie , could you come back in for a sec ?
( CHATTERING CONTINUES )
Dr. Weller ?
Hello ?
( DOOR CREAKING )
( UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING )
( SADIE BREATHING SHAKILY )
DR. WELLER : Can I help you with something ?
( GASPS )
Is everything all right ?
( ROCK MUSIC PLAYING )
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )